# **Reid Collins**

Brooklyn • New York • 646-250-2869 • <u>hihelloreid@gmail.com</u> • <u>hihelloreid.com</u> https://github.com/reidcollins

## **Programming Languages**

Perl, Ruby, bash

## **Operating Systems**

Linux, Unix, OSX

### **Web Technologies**

Perl w/ Catalyst, Ruby on Rails, Javascript (¡Query), HTML5/CSS3 (Bootstrap), AJAX, JSON, XML

### **Data Storage**

MySQL, SQL\*Loader, Postgres, MongoDB, BerkeleyDB, CDB

## **Deployment/Tools**

Heroku, AWS (EC2 & S3), Git, Subversion, Puppet, tinydns, Bind, pound

#### **Testing**

Agile BDD/TDD with Cucumber and RSpec, Test::Unit

#### Overview

I am a skilled software developer that equally enjoys writing efficient code and interacting with clients/stakeholders to build a better product. I have extensive development experience in an open source Agile environment, processing large data volumes, implementing new web applications, and managing client accounts.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# Cheetahmail, An Experian Company DEC, 2011 to JUL, 2013 Software Developer, Development Team

- Speed reporting of email marketing campaigns by utilizing SQL\*Loader to load high volume ad click/transaction data files into the database. Critical feature for account teams to speed subsequent campaigns.
- Implement Memcached to speed application performance. Work with database team to identify common bottlenecks, introducing Memcached to reduce the number of database gueries.
- Audit application for potential cross site scripting vulnerabilities and fix where needed. Work closely with Cheetahmail's financial clients to address their specific concerns preventing contract renewals.
- Liaise with QA engineers and Release teams to devise tests for software rollouts and fixed bugs when necessary. Assist in differentiating between code bugs and irregularities in virtual test environments.

# Cheetahmail, An Experian Company FEB, 2008 to AUG, 2011 Software Developer, Client Development Team

- Design and implement remarketing campaigns for clients. Build automated import processes that parse client data feeds from Coremetrics, Google Analytics, and Omniture to capture abandoned cart users, browsing customers, etc...
- Build automated process to convert customer's nightly inventory feeds from text or XML files into a

# **Reid Collins**

Brooklyn · New York · 646-250-2869 · <u>hihelloreid@gmail.com</u> · <u>hihelloreid.com</u> <u>https://github.com/reidcollins</u>

usable CDB or BerkeleyDB. Contents of these databases could then be dynamically inserted into mailing content via Cheetahmail API.

- Design automated report to measure attrition rate of client's subscriber lists. Compare client's incoming data files against bounced/unsubscribe addresses.
- Create automated scrubbing process, cleaning incoming data files against know spam traps, role addresses, and abuse addresses.
- Integration of client data imports/exports. Work closely with clients to design and implement customized solutions, aggregating performance metrics on a daily, weekly, monthly, or quarterly basis to synch with client or 3<sup>rd</sup> party database.
- Occasionally attend sales calls to explain complex technical/issues to prospective clients. Onboard new clients and assist with the integration of Cheetahmail's API suite.

# Cheetahmail, An Experian Company JAN, 2005 to FEB, 2008 Software Engineer, Operations Team

- 24 x 7 application and systems support (rotating on-call schedule). Responsible for supporting 750+ clients. Coordinate emergency outage response/recovery teams. Work with client services and clients to address all application related issues in an expedient manner.
- Respond to bug reports, providing 1<sup>st</sup>, 2<sup>nd</sup>, and 3<sup>rd</sup> tier support to clients and client services. Provide bug fixes or alternative solutions for clients highly sensitive to revenue loss.
- · Write one-off scripts to transform incoming client data into a usable format for the Cheetahmail database
- Write numerous scripts to automate daily tasks of the systems team (split files, cleanly terminate mailings, etc...)
- · Analyze and enhance queries for slow mailing campaigns segment counts
- Manage dns for 1200 domains delegated to Cheetahmail. Assist client's with configuration and help manage XML framework that centrally builds dns zone files for distribution across six name servers.

# Cheetahmail, An Experian Company JAN, 2001 to FEB, 2005 Client Relationship Manager, Client Services Team

- Manage 25+ clients from multiple verticals including catalog, financial, multi-channel retail, publishing, telecommunications, and travel.
- Manage production and strategy for top clients. Coordinate email marketing campaigns with client's other media (television, direct mail, web banner) initiatives.
- Enhance mailing content to bolster subscriber response, increasing click, open, and transaction rates.
- Help grow and maintain client subscriber lists by setting up registration forms, e-append, and viral marketing campaigns. Assist client in implementing Cheetahmail form coding to seamlessly capture data from client website.
- Attend sales calls with Cheetahmail sales team, demonstrating application to clients and fielding technical questions. Participate in contract renewals (100% retention rate)

## **Education**

Bachelor of Arts, Tulane University, 05/1998

Major: International Relations